## ana enders



www.anaenders.com ana.enders@gmail.com www.github.com/anaenders

profile

For some time now, I've been working closely with engineers, first as a Front-end Engineer and Designer, then as a Tech Lead and now as an Engineering Manager. I've spent the last 5 years at a startup where I joined as employee #3 (they've since raised several rounds and are at 135+ employees). I consider myself a generalist—shifting focus to whatever the business' needs are. I split my time between managing ten people and collaborating with the VP of Engineering and the CTO on behind-the-scences opperational fun. Having established our code standards for all our SASS, I review pull requests and work on features whenever I have bandwidth. When I'm not an individual contributor, or doing operational work, I dedicate my time to my direct reports, making sure they are happy, engaged, learning, and have what they need to be highly functional contributors.

education

2007 - 2008 | Parsons School of Design MFA Design + Technology

2001 - 2005 | Carnegie Mellon University BFA Music Performance, European Studies

likes

- · Interior design
- · Bea Arthur ice cream cones from Big Gay's
- · Home-made waffles
- Cuddles from my cat & dog while binge watching TV shows with Ian

dislikes

- IPAs
- · Winter and Summer
- Waking up early

experience

Engineering Manager - <u>The Muse</u> New York, NY - July 2012 - Present

Currently a manager to full-stack engineers, establishing code standards, performing code reviews, coding, and doing behind-the-scenes operation work. As a hiring manager, I've helped to recruit many of the engineers on the team. My strengths are in managing projects and people, and making sure everyone is happy and productive.

Freelance Font-end Developer - <u>Self Employed</u> San Francisco, CA - 07/2012 - 09/2011

Freelancing for old clients in need of front-end adjustments to their existing sites. Also worked on some logo and branding designs.

Clients: Tiffany & co. | Juice Generation | NewlyWish | Hackbright Academy

Front-end Developer - <u>Intersect NYC (a.k.a. Crown Partners a.k.a. Razorfish)</u> New York, NY - 09/2008 - 09/2011 (3 years 1 month)

As a member of the development team, I worked closely with the designers, backend programmers, and software engineers in producing custom e-commerse sites and content management software.

Clients: Kenneth Cole | Liz Claiborne | Boast USA | Carlos Falchi | Chilewich | Thornton Tomasetti | Yigal Azrouël

## profile expert advanced intermediate beginner Photoshop CSS HAML CoffeeScript MySQLRuby on ÷ UX & UI People JavaScript HTMLSASS Java Python Illustrator GraphicProject Rails Design Management Design Management